Register of the Timofei Fedotovich Tokarev Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Timofei Fedotovich Tokarev papers,
1903-1984
2001C31
Tokarev, Timofei Fedotovich
7 microfilm reels. (1.05 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, minutes, financial records, printed matter, and photographs, relating to Russian émigré affairs.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2001.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Biographical Note
Russian émigré organization official in the United States.
Scope and Content Note
Timofei Fedotovich Tokarev was a treasurer and vice-president of numerous Russian émigré organizations in San Francisco, including the Museum of Russian Culture, Russian Center, the Ob"edinennyi komitet russkikh natsional'nykh organizatsii v g. San Frantsisko (Consolidated Committee of the Russian National Organizations of San Francisco), the Russian Benevolent Trust Fund in Memory of V. P. and M. P. Anitchkoff, and Russkii Dom Sviatogo Vladimira. This collection consists mainly of material related to his work in these organizations. It is not clear how the papers of the Sedykh family and Fedor Semenov have found their way into this collection.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Russians--United States.; Russia.; United States.
Series Description
- Biographical File, 1953-1961. (Box 1)
  Certificates and clippings, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Correspondence, 1938-1961. (Box 1)
  Letters to Tokarev and his wife, arranged alphabetically by correspondent
- Subject File, 1909-1984. (Box 1-7)
  Correspondence, official documents and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject or name of organization in which Tokarev was active
- Photographs, 1903-1975. (Box 8)
  Negatives and prints originating from both the Tokarev and Sedykh families, and prints of members of the Russian Center and the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco
- Memorabilia, 1973-1977. (Box 8)
  Two commemorative plaques presented to T. F. Tokarev
Container List
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1953-1961 (Box 1)
  - Certificates (Folder 1: 1)
  - Clippings mentioning Tokarev (Folder 1: 2)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1938-1961.
  Includes letters to Tokarev's wife, Ilariia Mikhailovna (née Dol'skaia)
  - Smirnova-Boiarevich, Elena (H. Smirnoff), 1959-1961 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Soiuz russkikh voennykh invalidov v Bolgarii, 1938 (Folder 1: 4)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1909-1984
  - Fort Ross, California, 1935-1937
    - Booklet entitled Fort Ross: Avanpost byloi slavy Rossii v Amerike (K 125-letnemu iubileiu),1812-1937,istoricheskii album (Folder 1: 5)
    - Financial records. (Folder 1: 6)
      Includes ledger, receipts, sales reports all relating to production and sale of booklet
  - Holy Trinity Cathedral (Sviato-Troitskii Kafedralnyi Sobor), San Francisco, California, 1954-1977. (Folder 1: 7)
    Includes charter, bulletin and programs
  - Museum of Russian Culture, Inc., San Francisco, California, 1940-1976
    - Bulletins, 1940-1971 (Folder 1: 8)
    - Charter (Folder 1: 9)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1976 (Folder 1: 10)
    - Financial records
      - Checkbooks (Folder 1: 11)
      - Membership fees, 1948-1968 (Folder 1: 12)
      - Real estate records (Box 2)
        - New building acquisition (Folder 2: 1)
        - Rent (Folder 2: 2)
      - Receipt books (Folder 2: 3)
      - Receipts (Folder 2: 4-5)
      - Reports (Folder 2: 6)
      - Savings account statements (Folder 2: 7)
    - Minutes of meetings (Folder 2: 8)
  - Ob"edinennyi komitet russkikh natsional'nykh organizatsii v g. San Frantsisko, San Francisco, California (Consolidated Committee of the Russian National Organizations of San Francisco), 1936-1979 (Box 3)
    - Charter (Folder 3: 1)
    - Clippings (Folder 3: 2)
    - Correspondence
      - 1939-1950 (Folder 3: 3)
      - 1951-1955 (Folder 3: 4)
      - 1956-1958 (Folder 3: 5)
    - Financial records, 1940-1979
      - Checkbooks (Folder 3: 6)
      - Commercial account statements (Box-folder 4: 1)
      - Founding documents (Folder 4: 2)
      - Ledgers (Folder 4: 3)
      - Receipts (Folder 4: 4)
      - Reports (Folder 4: 5)
      - Tax records (Folder 4: 6)
    - List of member organizations (Folder 5: 1)
    - Minutes of meetings
      - 1936-1949 (Folder 5: 2)
      - 1950-1958 (Folder 5: 3)
    - Reports (Folder 5: 4)
    - Miscellany (Folder 5: 5)
  - Russian Benevolent Trust Fund in Memory of V. P. and M. P. Anitchkoff, San Francisco, California, 1951-1979
    - Financial reports (Folder 5: 6)
    - Founding documents (Folder 5: 7)
    - Liquidation documents (Folder 5: 8)
  - Russian Center of San Francisco, Inc., San Francisco, California, 1939-1980
    - Bulletins (Folder 5: 9)
    - Charters
      - General (Folder 5: 10)
      - Arbitration Court (Folder 5: 11)
    - Clippings, 1939-1951 (Folder 5: 12)
    - Correspondence, 1941-1980 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Financial records
      - General. (Folder 6: 2)
        Includes documents related to the celebration of the 75th anniversary of the Holy Trinity Cathedral
      - Financial reports (Folder 6: 3)
    - List of the board of directors (Folder 6: 4)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1940-1980 (Folder 6: 5)
  - Russkii Dom Sviatogo Vladimira (Russian Home of St. Vladimir), San Francisco, California, 1949-1979
    - Charter (Folder 6: 6)
    - Clippings (Folder 6: 7)
    - Concert programs (Folder 6: 8)
    - Minutes of meetings. (Box-folder 7: 1-2)
      Includes financial reports
    - Miscellany. (Folder 7: 3)
      Includes religious brochures and flyers
  - Russkoe Istoricheskoe Obshchestvo v Amerike, San Francisco, California. (Folder 7: 4)
    Includes minutes of meetings, 1937
  - Sanfrantsisskii Komitet Pomoshchi Russkim Voennym Invalidam Za Rubezhom (San Francisco Committee for the Aid of Russian Disabled Veterans Outside of Russia), San Francisco, California, 1960-1975
    - Clippings (Folder 7: 5)
    - Financial reports (Folder 7: 6)
  - Sedykh family, 1909-1984
    - Certificate of appreciation (Folder 7: 7)
    - Clipping about M. D. Sedykh (Folder 7: 8)
    - Correspondence between A. Sedykh, E. A. Vecherin (Vetchorine) and N. P. Mashevskii (Mashe), 1967-1969, and undated postcard from unidentified individual to M. Sedykh (Folder 7: 9)
    - Diaries and notes, 1969-1984 (Folder 7: 10)
    - Writings by Aleksandra Sedykh
      - "50-ti letnii iubilei Doma Miloserdiia," n.d. (Folder 7: 11)
        Holograph and typescript
      - "Fort Ross," Tserkovnaia zhizn', [1962]. (Folder 7: 12)
        Printed copy
      - "Russkoe istoricheskoe obshchestvo v Amerike," 1967 April 3. (Folder 7: 13)
        Typescript
      - "M. D. Sedykh," Russkaia Zhizn', 1967 May. (Folder 7: 14)
        Incomplete holograph and printed copy
    - Miscellany. (Folder 7: 15)
      Includes an issue of the periodical Monastyr, 1909 January
  - Semenov, Fedor (Semenoff, Theodore), 1925-1969. (Folder 7: 16)
    Includes certificates, receipts, photographs
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1903-1975. (Box 8)
  Negatives and prints originating from both the Tokarev and Sedykh (Sedich) families
  - Sedykh family - Prints and postcards depicting Mary Pickford, pictures of czar family, movie actors, and post cards (Folder 8: 1)
  - Tokarev family
    - Negatives (Folder 8: 2)
    - Print (Folder 8: 3)
  - Miscellany (unattributed photographs)
    - Negatives (Folder 8: 4)
    - Prints. (Folder 8: 5)
      Includes prints of the Russian Center and Museum of Russian Culture of San Francisco, California
- MEMORABILIA, 1973-1977. (Folder 8: 6)